# Ai-Chieh Lin

St. Louis, MO, 63005 | 314-397-9869 | linaichieh@gmail.com | Linkedin | GitHub

#### INFORMATICS PHARMACIST

MO-Certified pharmacist with PharmD degree, 4+ years of experience in mail order pharmacy and 2+ years of experience in a retail pharmacy setting. Made zero errors and was one of top performers for the past 5 years. Earned the champion of the month twice in 2019 and 2020. Got promoted to be a lead pharmacist in 2021. Highly motivated, organized, and versatile. Have great interests in data analysis, formulary, Pharmacoeconomics, and pharmacy benefit management. Possess advanced data analysis skill aiming to optimize pharmacy practices, improve patient safety, provide cost effective treatments and formulary.

#### TECHNICAL & INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

**Data Science Skills:** Python, Jupyter, Machine Learning, Pandas, Statistics, SQL, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel (pivot tables, data visualization).

**Interpersonal skills:** Good organizational ability, strong attention to detail, ability to multi-task efficiently in a fast-paced environment, perform tasks cooperatively as a team as well as independently, great problem-solving skills, bilingual **Certificates:** Medication Therapy Services, Pharmacy-Based Immunization Delivery, Cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR)

**Licenses:** License of Pharmacist, Missouri Board of Pharmacy (#2017036381)

Language: English, Mandarin

#### DATA SCIENCE PROJECTS

# **Hypertension and Stroke Prediction**

- Identified major risk factors for hypertension and stroke datasets from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES) from 2015 2020.
- Developed an investigational machine learning technique to accurately predict the risks for hypertension and stroke. Logistic Regression preprocessed with StandardScaler and OneHotEncoder used to predict the risk of getting stroke with an accuracy of 95% for as few as six features.
- Built a web application with simple inputs, features that are readily accessible for patients to keep track of their health condition with the ultimate goal of increasing a patients' compliance and awareness.

## Quantifying Impact of Electric Vehicle Charging Stations on Air Quality in the United States

- Analyzed electric vehicle (EV) trends on air quality with data collected from U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) and the U.S. Department of Energy
- Used Seasonal ARIMA model to forecast air quality levels, and a regression model to predict the number of charging stations that need to be installed to meet air quality reduction targets
- Created a tool to help policymakers and manufacturers identify a benchmark for charging station installations that will yield a 10% reduction in the number of days with poor air quality.

#### Classifying Subreddit Posts with Natural Language Processing: TravelHacks / AwardTravel

- Web scraped 4,000 posts from r/TravelHacks and r/AwardTracel, respectively. Cleaned the dataset with various approaches such as RegEx, tokenization, lemmatization, Python beautifulsoup.
- Analyzed the language to find the most popular words within each subreddit using CountVectorizer and TfidfVectorizer
- Used a MultinomialNB model with CountVector and GridSearch as the best model to predict where each post comes from with 91% accuracy

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Express Scripts, Lead Pharmacist**

St. Louis, MO, 10/2021 - 12/2022

- Served in a Lead role in the processing of mail-in prescriptions
- Provided expert assistance to team members with issues
- Maintained quality and productivity standards
- Acted as a liaison to resolve prescription order problems
- Collaborated with other teams to provide great service to patients

### **Express Scripts, Staff Pharmacist**

St. Louis, MO, 03/2018 - 09/2021

- Verified and confirmed validity of filled prescriptions in all area of pharmacy including controlled substances and Pet Meds
- Coached pharmacy technicians when quality slippage events occurred
- Accommodated patients' special handling requests
- Coordinated with lag team to ship out aged orders in a timely manner

### St. Louis College of Pharmacy, Student Researcher

St. Louis, MO, 06/2015 - 05/2017

- Assisted professors with research studies, experiments, and assays
- Collected and evaluated data statistically
- Presented a poster titled Development and Use of the Attitudes Toward Errors Scale for Health Care and Pharmacy Students at 2017 APhA Annual Meeting & Exposition

## Saint Louis University, Graduate Research Assistant

St. Louis, MO, 12/2009 - 05/2011

- Assisted professors with research studies, experiments, assays, and general lab maintenance
- Collected and evaluated data for statistical analysis
- Performed in vivo experiments on animal models
- Contributed to research works that were published in a scientific journal

## **Gang-Shong Drugstore, Pharmacist**

Taichung, Taiwan, 09/2004 - 06/2007

- Dispensed prescriptions with accuracy and attention to patient care
- Educated and advised patients on prescriptions and over the counter medications

## **EDUCATION**

## General Assembly, Data Science Immersive

Remote, Certificate Expected: 05/2023

- Exploratory data analysis, classical statistical modeling, machine learning models
- Programming language: Python, R, SQL

# St. Louis College of Pharmacy, PharmD, Pharmacy

St. Louis, MO, 08/2013 - 05/2017

- Cum Laude
- Relevant coursework: Therapeutics, Pharmacology, Pharmacy Law, Advanced compounding, Pharmacoeconomics
- Rotations: Essence Healthcare, SSM St. Clare Health Center, SSM Cancer Center, Barnes Jewish Hospital Pharmacy, Walgreens Pharmacy, Mercy Family Medicine, Mallinckrodt Pharmaceuticals, Vizient

### St. Louis University, MS, Biomedical Engineering

St. Louis, MO, 08/2007 - 05/2010

- 3.5 GPA
- Graduate research assistant: collected and analyzed data related to revascularization in vitro